（嘶嘶声）
(whooshing sound)
（贴纸弹出）
(sticker popping)
（嘶嘶声）
(whooshing sound)
在我们的很多例子中，
In a lot of our examples,
你将看到 DataCollators 一遍又一遍地弹出。
you're going to see DataCollators popping up over and over.
它们用于 PyTorch 和 TensorFlow 工作流程，
They're used in both PyTorch and TensorFlow workflows,
甚至在 JAX 中，
and maybe even in JAX,
但是没有人真正知道 JAX 中发生了什么。
but no-one really knows what's happening in JAX.
不过，我们确实有一个研究团队正在研究它，
We do have a research team working on it though,
所以也许他们很快就会告诉我们。
so maybe they'll tell us soon.
但是回到主题。
But coming back on topic.
什么是数据整理器？
What are data collators?
数据整理者整理数据。
Data collators collate data.
那不是很有帮助。
That's not that helpful.
但更具体地说，他们整理了一份样本清单
But to be more specific, they put together a list of samples
成一个单一的训练小批量。
into a single training minibatch.
对于某些任务，
For some tasks,
数据整理器可以非常简单。
the data collator can be very straightforward.
例如，当你进行序列分类时，
For example, when you're doing sequence classification,
数据整理器提供你真正需要的一切
all you really need from your data collator
是它将你的样品填充到相同的长度
is that it pads your samples to the same length
并将它们连接成一个张量。
and concatenates them into a single Tensor.
但对于其他工作流程，数据整理器可能非常复杂
But for other workflows, data collators can be quite complex
因为他们处理一些预处理
as they handle some of the preprocessing
该特定任务所需。
needed for that particular task.
所以，如果你想使用数据整理器，
So, if you want to use a data collator,
对于 PyTorch 用户，你通常通过数据整理器
for PyTorch users, you usually pass the data collator
到你的 Trainer 对象。
to your Trainer object.
在 TensorFlow 中，情况有点不同。
In TensorFlow, it's a bit different.
使用数据整理器的最简单方法
The easiest way to use a data collator
是将它传递给数据集的 to_tf_dataset 方法。
is to pass it to the to_tf_dataset method of your dataset.
这会给你一个 tensorflow_tf_data.dataset
And this will give you a tensorflow_tf_data.dataset
然后你可以将其传递给 model.fit。
that you can then pass to model.fit.
你将在示例中看到这些方法
You'll see these approaches used in the examples
和整个课程的笔记本。
and notebooks throughout this course.
另请注意，我们所有的整理器
Also note that all of our collators
采用 return_tensors 参数。
take a return_tensors argument.
你可以将其设置为 “pt” 以获取 PyTorch 张量，
You can set this to "pt" to get PyTorch Tensors,
&quot;tf&quot; 获取 TensorFlow 张量，
"tf" to get TensorFlow Tensors,
或 “np” 获取 Numpy 数组。
or "np" to get Numpy arrays.
出于向后兼容的原因，
For backward compatibility reasons,
默认值为 “pt”，
the default value is "pt",
所以 PyTorch 用户甚至不必设置这个参数
so PyTorch users don't even have to set this argument
大多数时候。
most of the time.
因此，他们通常完全没有意识到
And so as a result, they're often totally unaware
这个论点甚至存在。
that this argument even exists.
我们可以从中学到一些东西
We can learn something from this
也就是特权的受益人
which is that the beneficiaries of privilege
往往最无视它的存在。
are often the most blind to its existence.
不过还好，回来了。
But okay, coming back.
让我们看看一些特定的数据整理器是如何工作的。
Let's see how some specific data collators work in action.
虽然再次记住如果没有
Although again, remember if none
的内置数据整理器可以满足你的需求，
of the built-in data collators do what you need,
你总是可以自己写，而且它们通常很短。
you can always write your own and they're often quite short.
所以首先，我们将看到 “基本” 数据整理器。
So first, we'll see the "basic" data collators.
它们是 DefaultDataCollator 和 DataCollatorWithPadding。
These are DefaultDataCollator and DataCollatorWithPadding.
这些是你应该使用的
These are the ones you should use
如果你的标签很简单
if your labels are straightforward
并且你的数据不需要任何特殊处理
and your data doesn't need any special processing
在准备训练之前。
before being ready for training.
请注意，因为不同的模型
Notice that because different models
有不同的填充标记，
have different padding tokens,
DataCollatorWithPadding 将需要你模型的 Tokenizer
DataCollatorWithPadding will need your model's Tokenizer
所以它知道如何正确填充序列。
so it knows how to pad sequences properly.
默认的数据整理器不需要 Tokenizer 来工作，
The default data collator doesn't need a Tokenizer to work,
但它会因此抛出错误
but it will as a result throw an error
除非你所有的序列都是相同的长度。
unless all of your sequences are the same length.
所以，你应该意识到这一点。
So, you should be aware of that.
继续前进。
Moving on though.
许多其他数据整理器
A lot of the other data collators
除了基本的两个，
aside from the basic two are,
它们通常旨在处理一项特定任务。
they're usually designed to handle one specific task.
所以，我要在这里展示一对。
And so, I'm going to show a couple here.
这些是 DataCollatorForTokenClassification
These are DataCollatorForTokenClassification
和 DataCollatorForSeqToSeq。
and DataCollatorForSeqToSeq.
以及这些任务需要特殊整理器的原因
And the reason these tasks need special collators
是因为它们的标签长度可变。
is because their labels are variable in length.
在令牌分类中，每个令牌都有一个标签，
In token classification there's one label for each token,
标签的长度
and so the length of the labels
是序列的长度。
is the length of the sequence.
而在 SeqToSeq 中，标签是一系列标记
While in SeqToSeq the labels are a sequence of tokens
可以是可变长度，
that can be variable length,
那可能会非常不同
that can be very different
从输入序列的长度。
from the length of the input sequence.
所以在这两种情况下，我们处理整理那批
So in both of these cases, we handle collating that batch
也通过填充标签，
by padding the labels as well,
正如你在此示例中看到的那样。
as you can see here in this example.
因此，需要填充输入和标签
So, inputs and the labels will need to be padded
如果我们想加入可变长度的样本
if we want to join samples of variable length
进入同一个小批量。
into the same minibatch.
这正是数据整理者所做的
That's exactly what the data collators
而这正是这些数据整理者将为我们做的
and that's exactly what these data collators will do for us
你知道，为了这个特定的任务。
you know, for this particular task.
所以，有一个最终的数据整理器
So, there's one final data collator
我也想在本次讲座中向你展示。
I want to show you as well just in this lecture.
这就是 DataCollatorForLanguageModeling。
And that's the DataCollatorForLanguageModeling.
所以，这非常重要，首先，
So, it's very important, and it's firstly,
因为语言模型是如此基础
because language models are just so foundational
这些天我们用 NLP 所做的一切。
to do for everything we do with NLP these days.
但其次，因为它有两种模式
But secondly, because it has two modes
做两件截然不同的事情。
that do two very different things.
因此，你可以使用 mlm 参数选择所需的模式。
So you choose which mode you want with the mlm argument.
将其设置为 True 以进行掩码语言建模，
Set it to True for masked language modeling,
并将其设置为 False 以进行因果语言建模。
and set it to False for causal language modeling.
因此，为因果语言建模整理数据
So, collating data for causal language modeling
其实很简单。
is actually quite straightforward.
该模型只是做出预测
The model is just making predictions
接下来是什么标记，所以你的标签
for what token comes next, and so your labels
或多或少只是你输入的副本，
are more or less just a copy of your inputs,
整理人会处理
and the collator will handle that
并确保正确填充输入和标签。
and ensure that the inputs and labels are padded correctly.
但是，当你将 mlm 设置为 True 时，
When you set mlm to True though,
你会得到完全不同的行为，
you get quite different behavior,
这与任何其他数据整理器不同，
that's different from any other data collator,
那是因为将 mlm 设置为 True
and that's because setting mlm to True
表示掩码语言建模
means masked language modeling
这意味着标签必须是
and that means the labels need to be,
你知道，输入需要被屏蔽。
you know, the inputs need to be masked.
那么，那看起来像什么？
So, what does that look like?
所以，回想一下，在屏蔽语言建模中，
So, recall that in masked language modeling,
该模型没有预测下一个词，
the model is not predicting the next word,
相反，我们随机屏蔽掉一些标记
instead we randomly mask out some tokens
模型会同时预测所有这些。
and the model predicts all of them at once.
所以，它试图填补空白
So, it tries to kinda fill in the blanks
对于那些被屏蔽的令牌。
for those masked tokens.
但是随机掩蔽的过程出奇地复杂。
But the process of random masking is surprisingly complex.
如果我们遵循原始 BERT 论文中的协议，
If we follow the protocol from the original BERT paper,
我们需要用掩码标记替换一些标记，
we need to replace some tokens with a masked token,
一些其他带有随机令牌的令牌，
some other tokens with a random token,
然后保持第三组标记不变。
and then keep a third set of tokens unchanged.
是的，这不是讲座
Yeah, this is not the lecture
进入细节或我们为什么这样做。
to go into the specifics of that or why we do it.
你可以随时查看原始的 BERT 论文
You can always check out the original BERT paper
如果你好奇的话。
if you're curious.
写得很好。这很容易理解。
It's well written. It's easy to understand.
这里要知道的主要事情是它可能是一个真正的痛苦
The main thing to know here is that it can be a real pain
并且自己实施起来非常复杂。
and quite complex to implement that yourself.
但是 DataCollatorForLanguageModeling 会为你做
But DataCollatorForLanguageModeling will do it for you
当你将 mlm 设置为 True 时。
when you set mlm to True.
这是一个更复杂的例子
And that's an example of the more intricate
我们的一些数据整理人员所做的预处理。
preprocessing that some of our data collators do.
就是这样！
And that's it!
因此，这涵盖了最常用的数据整理器
So, this covers the most commonly used data collators
以及它们用于执行的任务。
and the tasks they're used for.
希望现在你会知道何时使用数据整理器
And hopefully, now you'll know when to use data collators
以及为你的特定任务选择哪一个。
and which one to choose for your specific task.
（嘶嘶声）
(whooshing sound)